翻译，校对，字幕制作：陌小念 【请勿商用】
姓名?
Name?
真真。
Zhenzhen.
大名
Real name.
赵红霞。
Zhao Hongxia.
哪里人?
Place of origin?
响水县梁桥村柳季寨
Liujizhai, Liangqiao Village, Xiangshui County.
来侨城好长时间了?
How long have you been in Qiaocheng?
五年。
Five years.
做什么工作的?
Occupation?
在梦巴黎做按摩师。
Massagist at Le Rêve Parisien.
这里有几张相片
Here are some photos,
帮我们辨认一下。
Please help us identifying them.
你看看这个戴头盔的人，
These guys with helmets,
有没有印象?
Do you recognise them?
看仔细点
Look closely.
戴起头盔哪个认得到?
How can I recognise someone with a helmet?
你是不是觉得
Do you think
我们在跟你开玩笑吗?
We're just joking?
涉枪案
It's a gun-related case.
“涉枪案”什么性质你懂不懂?
Do you know what a 'gun-related case' means?
我们走
Let's get it.
什么?
What?
搜
Let's get it.
你好，欢迎光临
Good morning, sir.
打劫
T's a robbery.
啊？你说什么?
I beg your pardon?
打劫!
It's a robbery!
全部蹲下来！
Get down!
蹲下来！
Down!
你吓我一跳!
You scared me!
站到!
Stop!
不要动!
Don't move!
手给我端起来!
Get down!
快点，快点!
Hurry up, hurry up!
还有四分钟!
We've got four minutes!
快点儿，快点儿!
Come on!
快，快，快，快!
Go go go go go go!
-走走! -走！
-Go Go! -Go!
-走撒! -走撒！
-Go! -Go！
尼玛没松离合走个锤子！
You're pressing the clutch!
啥子安?
What?
松离合!
Let it out!
哦!
OK!
你松你妈卖麻花儿哦松?
What the fuck are you doing?
你喊我松开离合器的嘛！
You told me to let out the clutch.
看个锤子看！
What are you looking at?
再看老子一枪给你龟儿子打过去!
I'll blow your head off if you keep staring!
滚!
再看老子一枪给你龟儿子打过去!
Fuck off!
I'll blow your head off if you keep staring!
滚!
Fuck off!
回来，灰雀儿!
滚!
Get back!
Fuck off!
回来，灰雀儿!
Get back!
快点儿，快点儿
Come on!
走了，走了，走了！
Let's get outta here.
长亭外，古道边
Beyond the arbour, beside old paths
芳草碧连天
The grass is green and joining the sky afar
这个楼房的老板儿高明
Gao Ming, the developer of these houses,
我借给他好大一笔钱
Borrowed a huge amount of my money.
他给我卷钱跑了
But now he took the money and got away.
我只能当他死了
I can only take that as if he's dead.
天天给他奔丧
I'll hold funeral for him every day.
你们说好不好?
How does that sound?
刘吴!
Liu Wu!
放老子下来！
Get me down!
放老子下来！！！
让他下来。
Put him down.
还哇呜乱叫不？
Still barking?
你是保安
You're a guard,
不是公安，晓得不?
Not a cop, you know that?
你狗门孃看门狗
You guard the gate for Gao Ming,
孝顺的很嘛~嘿嘿嘿嘿
What a loyal dog.
啊！我把他卵捏爆！
I'll crumb his balls!
来啊!
Come on!
来撒!
为持续打造我市生态文化旅游品牌
As a showcase of our city's ecotourist landscape,
丰富人民的文化活动
And cultural diversity,
由市旅游委举办的烟花晚会
The firework parade organised by thetourist board
将于今晚9点举行。
Will be held tonight at nine o'clock.
那时，我市大部分地区
By then the beautiful firework can be viewed
都可以欣赏到这场美丽的烟花
In the entire Xishan area.
据了解，晚会的项目组
According to the parade organiser,
一共准备了一万余支烟花
More than ten thousand firecrackers
覆盖了高低空各种型号
Of various types and sizes were prepared.
整个燃放过程将持续25分钟。
The spectacle will last for 25 minutes in total.
不要动。
Don't move.
你
Don't you
不热吗?
Feel hot in that?
转过去
Look away.
老子喊你转过去了哇！
I said Look away.
暴露了!暴露了！
You're exposed!
拿几袋钱
Put it on.
拿个锤子呀拿
Put on what?
你也取了
You take it off too.
我不取
I won't.
暴露了！暴露了！
Don't get me exposed!
我暴露就是你暴露
You're already exposed when I am.
晓得不?
Got that?
暴露。
Exposed.
暴露
累死老子了
It's stifling.
兄弟。
Bro.
哪个是你兄弟?
Who's your bro?
女的？
She's a lady.
妹娃儿
Lass.
既然你已经看到我们的样子了，
Since you already know how we look like,
江湖规矩
According to the principles,
我今天必须要灭你的口。
Today I'll have to do away with you.
灭你的口
Do away with you.
只能说你命不好
Blame it on your own bad luck.
命太不好了
Your luck's so bad.
-为啥子不关窗子？-为啥不关...
Why didn't you shut the window?
还好不关窗子
Thank God she didn't.
找下药，行不行？
Get the medicine, will you?
好，好好...
OK, OK.
听招呼，我就不灭口
I won't kill you if you do what I say.
没得事的，放松点
It's OK. Relax.
放松啊。
I'm relaxed.
放松了你一动不动
You aren't relaxed.
坐的梆硬
You're sitting so still.
废了，残废了
I'm a cripple!
所以说，这个命啊
That's what I call a bad luck.
那你平时生活啷个办呢？
How do you live your life?
有个保姆
I have a carer.
嗯...
Emm.
出来!
Get out!
老子看到你了！
I've seen you!
你是不是在门后头?
Are you behind the door?
还是在窗子后头?
Or behind the window?
走了。
She's gone.
遭我骂起跑了
I yelled her away.
那你屋头还有其他人没得呢?
Is there anyone else in your flat?
都死球了,
All died out,
就剩我一个
I'm the only one left.
所以说，这命啊
That's a really bad luck.
你莫骗老子哈！
Don't you make a fool of me.
爱信不信
Believe it or not.
龟儿态度好点儿哈
Watch your attitude.
有点儿太不尊重人了
You're too disrespectful.
这儿是哪个掌握局势？
You gotta get it straight,
龟儿搞不清楚状....啊！
Who's in control now.
你咋子?
What are you doing?
拔钉子。
Pulling out the nail.
又是咋子?
What now?
上药
Putting on medicine.
倒你妈批啥子药？
What medicine?
红花油
Safflower oil.
红花油是治跌打损伤的
Safflower oil is for bone injuries,
伤口涂不得
It can't be applied to wounds.
你那个伤口要先消毒
Gotta disinfect your wound first.
消毒!
Disinfect it!
消毒 消毒 消毒 消毒 消毒。
Disinfect.
哪个是消毒的?
Which one's for disinfection?
酒精。
Alcohol.
酒精 酒精
等到 等到
Wait.
这个怕是有点痛哦
It's gonna hurt a bit?
它又不痛
It doesn't hurt.
哎哟~
ai~yo~
那么疼哦?
It hurts so bad?
不是说不疼吗?
Didn't you say it doesn't hurt?
啊痛点儿就痛点儿嘛
Just some sting.
反正是消毒了
It's disinfection.
你
You
把那个小瓶瓶儿的粉粉儿撒进去
Apply the powder from that samll bottle,
纱布包起来就行了
Bind it up, and it'll be fine.
这个瓶瓶儿?
纱布包起来就行了
This one?
Bind it up, and it'll be fine.
这个瓶瓶儿?
This one?
这个痛不?
Does this one hurt?
不痛
No.
你不是说不痛嘛？
Didn't you say it doesn't hurt?
他啷个那么怕痛哦?
Who knows he's such a coward.
我觉得不痛
I don't feel it!
我觉得都不痛
I don't feel pain at all.
你肯定觉得不痛
Of course you can't feel a thing!
龟儿再说，老子...
I'll blow your head off,
老子一枪打死你信不信？
If you carry on with your prank.
冷静，冷静....
Calm down.
一枪打死你，你信不信！？
I'll blow your head off!
包起就好了
I'll bind it up and you'll be fine.
包起就好了，好了，好了，好了...
bind it up and you'll be fine.fine.fine.fine.
老马
Ma.
没有事吧？
You're OK?
你在搞啥子名堂?
What the hell are you doing?
说话!
Answer it!
警察警察救命呐~~~
Help me, officer!
任队长。
Captain Ren.
是那样的
I'll tell you what.
高明卷了我的钱跑了
Gao Ming took my money and got away.
我也没得办法呀
I was really backed into a corner.
我来合法要钱
I'm legally collecting debt,
他的门卫马先勇，先动手打的我嘛
It was his guard Ma Xianyong punched me first.
要得
Alright.
把你兄弟伙那些都喊起
Gather your men,
我们回去慢慢儿说
Let's talk about it at our place.
我们只是在这里耍的
We're just hanging out here.
我不是那个意思。
I didn't mean that.
那你啥子意思嘛?
What do you mean then?
我们换个地方耍，啊
Let's hang out somewhere else.
走
Let's go.
你不能走!
You can't go!
让开，退后！
What're you doing? Back off!
医药费
My medical bills.
你要给我医药费
You gotta pay my medical bills.
没有医药费你不能走!
You aren't going before you pay!
包包拿来
Gimme my bag.
就那么多了
That's all.
马先勇
Ma Xianyong,
你给老子记到哈
Mark my words,
告诉你老板儿高明
Tell your boss Gao Ming,
喊他不要躲了啊
Stop hiding.
他要再不出来
If he doesn't come out,
老子天天给他开追悼会
I'll hold funeral for him everyday.
刘吴！
Liu Wu.
你娃莫太嚣张了哈
Don't go too far.
太嚣张了!
He's way too far!
走!
Go!
我们走吧,小伙子们!
Let's go, lads!
我们走吧!
Let's go!
任队长。
Captain Ren.
任队长,
Captain Ren,
我有重要的事情向你汇报
I have to report you something important.
又有啥子事嘛？
What this time?
哎呀……
Errr…
不好说
It's hard to say.
走撒，走撒，都走撒
Get outta here!
哎呀，你莫搞那些神神秘秘的
Stop acting mysterious,
我晓得你啥子意思
I know what you want.
还是考协警嘎嘛
To apply at the auxiliary unit again.
我跟你说好多回了
I've told you many times,
你这个标准达不到，考不起
You won't pass the test with your level.
走嘛
Let's go.
莫打架了，几十岁的人了
Stop fighting. You're too old for that.
等哈儿，等哈儿
Wait, wait.
我有重要的东西要给你
I'll give you an important stuff.
你哪点儿学的这歪门邪道的哦
Where have you learnt all these crooks?
我不是要给你送礼
It's not bribery.
几天前，工地上挖出了个东西
A couple of days ago, they dug this stuff out from the site,
这个东西很危险
A very dangerous stuff.
要是落到犯罪份子手头
It's gonna be a disaster
要出大事情的啊
If it ends up in criminals' hands.
等一哈
Wait a sec.
好说歹说
I made quite an effort
从那农民工手里搞过来
To get it from two workers.
这也算是立功
It can count as a service I rendered.
你给领导，打个招呼嘛
Please let the superiors know.
马先勇
Ma Xianyong.
我想代表我们领导，谢谢你
I thank you on be half of our superiors.
咋回事，这是咋回事呢
What? What happened?
老马
Ma,
你凶得很啊
You're such a thug, aren't you?
逗我队长耍么
Are you jerking the captain around?
搞错了
It's a mistake!
咋子喃？你还真有枪哦？
What? You really have a gun?
我真有枪
I really do have one!
这个就是你的枪？
Is this your gun?
不是
No.
你真是裤裆里面拉二胡
You're really a good for nothing,
扯卵弹
Apart from talking shit.
枪丢了，是不是你回来拿走了
The gun, did you come back and took it?
枪,
The gun,
是真的么？
Is it real?
你明天看新闻
Watch the news tomorrow
就晓得是真的么假的了
Then you'll know if it's real.
是真的…
Is it real...
今天你能撞到我们兄弟伙这种...
Bumping into badasses like us -
杀人如麻勒悍匪
The deadliest mass killers,
也算是你人生中不可多得的经历
Is quite a precious experience for you.
但是也莫怕
But don't be scared,
我们借你的地方
We're using your place
避下风头就走了
To stay away from troubles for a minute.
你好好儿配合
You'll be fine
没得事
If you cooperate well.
那我要是不配合
But will you fire at me
你会不会开枪呢？
If I refuse to cooperate?
开枪你就死求了
You'll be dead once he fires.
那我就不配合
I won't cooperate then.
老子给你龟儿脸了是不是？
Don't test my nerves.
我忍你好久了我跟你说
I've tolerated you for quite a long time.
我忍耐是有限度勒哦
And there's a limit in my tolerance.
那你就开枪撒
Then fire at me.
你想试一下是不是
Do you want to try?
我打赌你不敢开
I bet you don't have the guts.
日……
What the…
哎呀，搞啥子嘛...
What are you doing?
算了算了算了
Cut it out,
好不好嘛
Please!
她是个残废
She's a cripple,
老壳还是憨勒
And a dumbass.
你龟儿才憨
You're a dumbass!
开枪嘛
Fire!
老子数三声儿哈
I'll count to three.
数三声儿你不开枪
Count to three,
你就是个哈批
If you don't fire then you're a coward!
三!
Three!
二,三,四……
Two, three, four…
消消气，消消气哈……
Calm down, calm down...
你跟他道个歉
Apologise to him
这个事情就过去了嘛
And we'll forget about it!
二！
Two.
一 ！！！
One!
疯婆娘，疯婆娘，让我日到你个婆娘
She's crazy!
走走走走走...
Let's go!
老子闯到起老
what fuck i meet
-你要去哪点儿? -真的是龟儿好疯哦
Where are you going?
疯了，疯了...
Crazy!
你要去哪里?站到!
Where are you going? Stop!
屁大个憨批
You dumbass!
啊你不是憨批
You dumbass, too!
站到！你不是要开枪吗？
Stop! Didn't you want to shoot me?
开你妈~
Shut up.
开枪撒
Shoot then!
站到！！！
Stop!
咋子啊？去哪点儿？
What are you doing?
你开枪满
Fire at me!
哎哟~你那个眼睛
What happened to your eyes?
又打架是不是啊
Went to fight again?
撞滴，啥子打架
I bumped into something.
这个岁数了一天到晚去惹事
Still looking for troubles at your age?
来，把鸡蛋吃了
Eat the egg.
不。
No.
四块五，啊四块钱就行了嘛
Four and five, ah, four dollars will do
太多了，太多了
It's too much.
不多....
Not really.
二十二，二十二...
Twenty-two.
就这样就这样
Gimme credit.
就这样？
On credit again?
我给你讲哈哦，我表妹那个事情
Have you considered my proposal?
你考虑下嘛
My cousin I mentioned before?
你表妹我就不考虑了
I'm not considering your cousin,
要考虑就考虑你
I'll consider you instead.
哦哟，你真的是，不要开这种玩笑哈
Don't make fun of me.
真的是乱讲哦
Cut the crap.
这高一入学工作都块结束了
The enrolment for Senior 1 is about to finish,
学费不能再拖了
The payment can not be delayed.
嗯嗯
Yes, yes,
我今天来就是为了解决这个问题的
I came here exactly for this issue today.
学杂费和住宿费你看一下
Take a look at the fees for tuition and accommodation.
住宿费...
Accommodation?
还有个住宿费？
Why is there an accommodation fee?
马依依申请学校住校啊
Yiyi applied for school housing.
她说和你商量过的
She said she's discussed it with you.
你不知道啊？
Don't you know that?
一千...八百五？
One thousand eight hundred and fifty?
我们都是按标准收费的
We always charge by standards,
你要是不放心啊
If you have any doubt,
可以去官网上查一下
You can look up the rates on our website.
放心，放心
Not at all.
学校我是绝对放心
I have absolutely no doubt about the school.
那就好
That's good.
吴老师
Ms. Wu.
你看哈
Look,
最近我是...手头比较紧
My budget is a bit tight recently.
买了个房子嘛
I just bought a flat.
你有钱买房没钱交学费啊？
So you have money for a flat but not for the tuition fee?
我先打个欠条
I'll write you an IOU.
我要你欠条做啥子...
I don't want your IOU.
我们要收的是学费
We need the tuition fee.
你要相信我嘛
You gotta trust me.
不是信不信的问题
It has nothing to do with trust.
要是家长都像你这样
Our school's gonna shut down,
那我们学校啷个办下去？
If all parents are like you.
学费，学费
The tuition fee
她要是学好了
Will definitely be paid,
我肯定交嘛
If she studies well.
你这话啥子意思
What do you mean?
等于是...
So,
她学不好你就不交学费咯？
You won't pay if she doesn't study well?
我不是这个意思!
That's not what I mean!
那你啥子意思?
What do you mean then?
你啥子意思嘛?
What do you mean?
啊呀...
ah ya...
吴老师，吴老师
Ms. Wu, please.
唉哟哟哟，不要不要不要
No, no, no.
你拿着
Please take them.
我不要！
I can't!
哎呀！
Ah!
洒了
They fell off.
哎呀...
Too bad.
咋子了嘛？
What happened?
依依。
Yiyi.
他又咋子你了？
What did he do to you?
过来！
Come here!
跑啥子跑？
Why did you run away?
过来！
Come here!
跑啥子跑
That's what you get,
When you run away.
跑啥子跑
why did you run?
马叔叔，你给我个面子
Uncle Ma, please do me a favour.
走开！
Get lost!
跑！
Run!
马先勇！
Ma Xianyong!
你个死保安！
You bloody security guard!
哪一个给老子贴的罚单？
Who stuck this ticket?
狗日的，老子是个警察
fuck! I'm a cop.
出任务
I'm on duty here.
给老子贴罚单
Whoever did it,
不要让我看到
Don't let me find out,
看到把你腿打断！
Or I'll beat your leg off!
老子贴勒罚单
I issued the ticket.
你给老子下来
Get off, you!
you call me down i go down
你叫老子下来老子就下来
你晓不晓得我哪一个？
The details of the crime scene are not yet clear.
市公安局已经赶至案发现场
The police force has arrived at the scene
展开案件的侦破工作
To start investigation.
相关道路也暂时封闭
The surrounding roads are temporarily closed.
又是你个狗日的
我台记者正在前往现场
Our reporters are on their way.
莫事就冒充警察
而关于抢劫案的进一步信息
As the investigation goes on,
-给老子下来下来 -你走嘛，你走嘛！
我台也将持续报道
Further reports will be followed by our channel.
把我腿打断！来来来！
已有案发地周围的民众
There have been witnesses of the incident
确认劫匪持有枪支
Approving that the robbers had a gun.
下来
在这里也要提醒广大群众
We have to remind our listeners,
注意您的人生安全
To pay attention to your safety,
即时向警方举报可疑人员
And report any suspicious personnel to the police.
老子......
What the…
老黄
Huang,
那个马先勇和我们队长
How exactly is that Ma
到底是啥子关系嘛
Related to our captain?
那个马先勇....
That Ma Xianyong
以前还算是个不错的人
Was quite a good guy before.
就是命不好
He just had a bad luck.
那个时候...我们队长
When our captain
刚刚从公安大学毕业
Just graduated from the police academy,
到派出所
He was assigned to our station
带的那个协警
With an auxiliary police officer.
这是他
That was him.
老马搞协警拼的很，不要命
Ma worked very hard and was brave as a lion.
也帮队长破了一些案子
He also helped the captain solving some cases.
吃亏就吃亏在，没得啥子文化
But unfortunately he wasn't well educated,
一个公务员转正
He tried the civil service test
考了四五年
For over four or five years.
好不容易考起了
When he finally passed the test,
-然后咧？ -队长结婚办酒
Ma got himself dead drunk
老马喝的一塌糊涂
At our captain's wedding.
但哪个晓得
But you know what,
喝醉了他还非要开车
He insisted on driving after drinking so much.
刚过个路口，就撞了
The car crashed just over the crossing,
120都还没到
His wife passed away
他的老婆，就没得了
Before the ambulance arrived.
咋还有人取现？
Why are there people taking cash out?
这儿是银行哒嘛
Of course, it's a bank.
只准存不准取嗦？
Deposit only, no withdrawal?
你要保护好现场嘛
You have to keep the scene intact.
你你你你...这走来走去的，现场都破坏了
The scene is ruined with people walking around.
遭抢的是隔壁手机店，不是这儿
It was the phone store next door got robbed, not here.
手机店?
The phone store?
拿枪抢劫手机店?
They robbed a phone store with a gun?
所以说我说是两个憨贼哒嘛
That's how I say they're retarded.
你说两个憨贼拿着枪...
You said the robbers were holding a gun?
你看到没得那个枪是啥子样子？
Have you seen how the gun looked like?
肯定看到了撒
Of course I have.
老子正好出来
I just came out,
那个憨贼还拿枪对到我
And that idiot had his gun pointing at me.
嘿的我转身就跑
That scared shit out of me so I ran inside.
我一想不对
But I thought that wasn't enough,
我又回来把铁门把它关起了
So I came back to shut the gate.
枪是啥样子?
How did the gun looks like?
你是哪个?
Who are you?
我是哪个?
Who am I?
你说我是哪个？
Don't you know who I am?
枪啊
The gun,
枪有点长
Was a bit long.
大概那么长的样子
About this long.
就像是寨子里头的土猎枪
Just like those shotguns for hunting you'd find in villages.
土猎枪?
A shotgun for hunting?
那两个憨贼还在手机店里放了一枪
Those two idiots fired a shot in the shop.
放了一枪?
They fired a shot?
诶
Yeah.
还有呢?
What else?
没得了
That's it.
再想想
Think harder.
真勒没得了
Nothing else.
搞啥子？
What are you doing?
不是...啥子意思哦？
What do you mean?
你啥子意思哦?
What do YOU mean?
你在抢我啊?
Are you robbing me?
莫得啊
Not at all.
你保安不过关
You aren't qualified as a security guard,
经不住考验
You failed my test.
尼玛...
fuck
给我弄出去
Get him out.
走嘛，走嘛
Go away.
你又要做啥子嘛？
What are you doing here?
我是想帮忙嘛
I just wanna help.
我晓得你想帮忙
I know you wanna help,
你现在是...
But you've gone too far.
我是好心
It's out of good intention.
我知道你好心
It's very kind of you.
我们已经乱七八糟了
But we're in a mess here,
你回去干工地
Go back and guard your site.
我不走我不走
I'm not going.
你要做啥子？
What next?
我没有吃早餐
I haven't had breakfast.
那你去吃撒
Go ahead and have some.
你看你们那么多粉儿
You've got so much pho.
那都是吃剩得
These are all leftovers.
没关系嘛...不要浪费
Fine with me. Don't waste it.
随便你，啊，吃，吃，随便你
Alright, go ahead.
这个头盔还有点儿性感哦
The helmet is quite posh.
查一下
Search it.
找人去城里头所有车行都问了
We've asked all the motorcycle dealers across the town,
暂时还没得消息
No trace's been found yet.
就怕是在网上买勒
I'm afraid it was bought online.
马上把相片发给网络班的同事
Send the photos to the department of Internet security,
喊他们上网去搜
And ask them to search online.
只要有卖跟这一样勒
Call every seller
都打电话去问
Who sells the same model.
要的
Yes, sir.
老黄
Huang,
枪呢?
What about the gun?
弹道分析...还在做
Ballistic analysis is on the way,
从天花板上
The bullet fragments
拿出来的子弹碎片
That we took out from the ceiling
拿去分析了
Have been sent for analysis.
结果很快就出来
The results are coming out soon.
哦，还有
Other than that,
这个铁锤上的指纹
The fingerprints on the hammer
马上拿去对比
Will be sent to compare soon.
狗日的，两个劫匪
Two robbers,
一把枪
One gun.
龟儿枪都敢开为啥放弃银行不抢
Why have they only robbed the store but not the bank,
抢手机店儿呢
If they have guts to fire a gunshot?
队长
Captain!
有线索
We've found something.
队长
Captain,
这个人叫陈波波
This guy's called Chen Bobo,
外号波仔
Nickname's Bobby.
是梦巴黎的领班
He's the head waiter of Le Rêve Parisien.
就是这个头盔
That's the helmet.
发燃
Get him.
又吵架了?
Having a row again?
牛奶咋不拿进去?
Why didn't you take the milk inside?
我自己进去了哈
I'm coming in myself.
你妈卖麻批你个死老头儿
Don't you ever get in here, you old bastard!
给老子滚远点儿
Get the fuck outta here!
你今天儿要是进来
If you dare to take one step inside
老子不喊人弄死你个龟儿子个鬼
I'll yell the shit out of you!
你个老不死的龟孙子
You cocksucking, dirt-eating twat!
该背时没得人给你送终
You gonna rot in your tomb alone!
你就等到一个人老死在屋头
Go home and wait for the maggots
没得人收尸，臭了都没得人管！！！
To eat you dirty scumbag alive!
啊
ah
一大早吃火药了哦
Why're you so mad?
火气那么大
What made you so mad in the morning?
今天是我的生日...
It's my birthday.
滚！
Fuck off!
哦
ok
站到
Stop.
去哪点儿？
Where are you going?
大，大，大，大姐...
Madam,
走了
We're leaving.
再见...
Goodbye.
啊说来就来，说走就走？不准走！
It's not a tourist sight. Dare you leave.
老子就是要走
I am leaving.
你飞过来咬我撒?
Wanna fly over and bite me?
你走试一哈儿
You can try.
你一走老子马上就喊人
And I'll shout once you take a step out.
老练
Don't go!
去把那个疯婆娘嘴巴给老子堵起
Stuff the mouth of that crazy bitch.
堵起，堵起
Stuff her mouth.
你敢靠近我，我就喊
I'll shout if you dare to come forward.
老子喊了，站到！欸！
I'm shouting, stop!
退后
Back off.
再退
One more step.
好，就在那里
OK stay there.
站好
Stand still.
怕了嗦
Scared?
不是悍匪么？
Aren't you mass killers?
不是杀人如麻么？
The deadliest ones?
啷个连个残废都搞不定哦
Can't deal with a cripple?
两个憨批
Dumbasses.
你到底要，搞啥子嘛...
What do you want?
我们就是路过勒...
We're just passing by.
放我们走就完了嘛
Just let us leave.
按规矩来撒
We should stick to the principles.
我都看了你们样子了
I've seen your faces.
你们不灭我的口
How can you get away
啷个跑的脱呢？
Without getting rid of me?
一枪打死我，打死我了就走
Shoot me dead then you can go.
哦，你喊我打死你？
Are you ordering me?
你是我妈么？
Are you my mom?
批好怪哦
How strange.
老子就不打死你
I'm not shooting you dead.
你不打死我就不能走
You're not going if you don't shoot me.
不走就不走
Fine, I'm not going.
老子们有的是时间
We've got plenty of time.
坐起
Sit down.
要是钱没凑齐，你还会回来？
Will you be back if you can't get enough money?
凑不凑齐都回来
I'll be back no matter what.
把工地看好
Take care of the site for me.
今天下午
They dug this out today,
工地上挖出来的
From the site.
我试过
I've tried it,
还能开
It still works.
你要拿这个东西...
You gonna use this
去跟债主干仗？
To fight the debt collectors?
狗日可以哦
How brave you are.
高老板儿
Mr. Gao.
你看
Look,
我在你楼盘买了套房子
I've bought one of your flats,
首付款10万块钱是借的
And I borrowed one hundred thousand for the down payment.
现在楼盘停了
Now the construction work's been shut down,
不能能把十万块钱还我
Can you give me back my money?
我要是不给你钱
So you'll fire at me
你要向老子开枪是不是？
If I don't give you the money back?
我不是这个意思
That's not what I meant.
高老板儿
Mr. Gao.
还我嘛
Gimme back the money,
Please.
还我嘛...
马先勇
Ma Xianyong,
你狗日的要是打死我
If you shoot me,
妈的狗日的你一分钱都拿不到你不晓得？
You'll never get a penny.
今晚八点
Tonight at eight o'clock,
西山大桥
Xishan Bridge,
我要给未来区老板儿高明
I'll hold a funeral for Gao Ming,
开追悼会
The developer of La Lune Bleue.
父老乡亲走过路过不要错过
Welcome, everyone!
来凑个热闹
Don't miss the spectacle!
Oh, ma'am, your bracelet is so pretty
唉，大姐，你手镯挺好看啊
怎么打的，会不会打嘛
What's this game?
三个人打不过一个...
Can't beat an old bag with three men?
波仔！
Bobby!
站到
Stop!
波仔，站到！
Bobby, stop!
波仔
Bobby!
站到
Stop!
小心!
Xiangjie, watch out!
波仔，站到
Bobby, stop!
站到，波仔
stop！bobby!
波仔，不要跑！
bobby,don`t go
站到！
stop！
Stop!
不要跑！
don`t run!
波仔！
bobby！
你看嘛看？看什么看？
What are you looking at?
走不走嘛？
Wanna a lift?
去梦巴黎多少钱？
How much to Le Rêve Parisien?
二十
Twenty.
十五，十五啦，十五啦~
Fifteen.
上车
Get in.
啊！你要干什么！放开我！
What do you want? Untie me!
我不是你
I'm not you.
城里头
Everyone in the town
哪个晓不得我高明
Knows that I, Gao Ming
出了事，欠了钱，就跑路
Ran away from my debts.
我又咋个做人安
I can't live with such a bad name.
你们咋个做人
You can't live with it?
想没想过我咋个做人喃？
Have you thought about how I'll live with it?
你晓不晓得好多人在我背后指我脊梁骨
Do you know how many were talking behind my back?
说我是小三儿
They said I'm your mistress,
是婊子
I'm a bitch.
老子为了你离婚...
I divorced for your sake,
老婆娃娃都不要了
And dumped my wife and kid.
骗子!
Liar!
妈勒，都是骗子!
Everyone's a liar!
老子爱上你
I am die
老子就死了
When I fell in love with you.
再给老子说一句？
What did you say?
-再说一句，你再给老子说一遍 -不要打，老子！
Say that again!
你戳到我眼睛了
You poked my eye!
你还要打！
You asked for it!
你不要气
You stay away from this.
大人的事就让大人去弄嘛
Let the adults solve their own issue.
这个不是大人的事情
It's not an issue between adults.
是男人的事情
It's between men.
依依！依依！
Yiyi!
高翔
Gao Xiang,
人都给你喊得差不多了
We got you quite a lot followers now.
七七八八，喊了一百多个
We've gathered more than a hundred from everywhere.
说嘛，搞哪个妈的
What's the mission?
今天晚上
Tonight,
找刘武
We'll go meet Liu Wu.
是不是他给你老汉儿办追悼会那个事情嘛
Is it because he's holding a funeral for your old man?
我说了好多遍
I've told you many times,
我老汉儿肯定要回来
My dad will come back.
他欠刘武这么多钱
He owes Liu Wu too much money,
我老汉儿一个人肯定要出大事
They'll definitely come to him.
真打起来，搞不好我爸要遭弄死
They might beat my dad to death.
我就是要让他开不成追悼会
I'll screw up this funeral.
一句话
Let's cut the bullshit,
找刘武，敢不敢？
Do you have the courage?
翔撒
Xiang.
你听我一句劝
Listen to me.
我们这样子去打，打得赢不嘛
Surely we can't win if we really gonna fight.
是去救我爸
We're rescuing my dad!
打得赢，要救
It's not a matter of winning or loosing.
打不赢更要救
I gotta fight them no matter what.
你们要是不敢来
I don't blame you,
我不怪你们
If you dare not to come.
你们要是跟着我去
But if you're coming with me,
今天七点，就在这儿集合
We'll meet here tonight at seven.
根据现场目击者称
According to the eyewitnesses,
两名戴头盔的劫匪
The two robbers with helmets
先是在信用社门口停留了一会儿
Stopped for a while in front of the bank,
然后冲进这家手机店，实施了抢劫
Before dashing into this phone store.
本台记者采访到了刑警支队副队长任晓聪
I'm here with Ren, the vice-captain of the police squad.
您好
Good morning.
诶，你好
这起案件现在已经引发多方关注
This case has attracted wide attention
能否透露一下，大致是个什么情况呢？
Could you brief us what's the situation in general?
我晓得这一天儿迟早要来
I knew this today was gonna come,
但没想到嫩个快
But never expected it to be so soon.
大头
Big Head,
我们混出头了
We're famous now.
这两名劫匪都持有武器
The two robbers were armed,
非常危险的
They're very dangerous.
出个锤子头了，出头
How come are we famous?
戴个头盔，哪个晓得是我们
Nobody's gonna recognise us with helmets on.
龟儿懂个锤子
You dumb idiot.
哪个大人物是轻易露脸的
Big shots don't expose their faces easily.
蜘蛛侠,
Spiderman,
蝙蝠侠,
Batman,
钢铁侠,
Iron Man,
神雕大侠？
Eagle Man,
哪个不戴面具？
They all wear masks.
以后我们兄弟伙行走江湖
From now on in the underworld,
组合就叫
Our gang will be known as
头盔侠
The Helmetmen.
The Helmetman.
抢手机店儿勒头盔侠？
The phone-shop-robbing Helmetmen?
你们两个憨批
You two dumbasses.
她是不是，在嘲笑我们?
Is she laughing at us?
今晚九点的烟花晚会…
The firework parade at nine'o clock tonight...
不要张她
Just ignore her.
你看的哪本儿嘛
What are you reading?
字认得全不？
Can you read all the characters?
耶,水浒
Ah, Water Margin.
有点儿深度啊
That's quite profound.
那本儿可以
It's a nice book since it has pinyin,
嗯，那本儿有拼音
Which can help you read.
眼睛儿
Bra,
吃饭了
Lunch time.
好，马上
Alright.
眼镜儿？
Bra?
你又不戴眼镜儿
Why does he call you Bra?
为啥要叫眼镜儿喃？
You're not wearing one.
你梳个鸡冠头
Why not Chicken-head?
为啥子不叫鸡冠呢？
It fits your hairstyle.
小的时候
When we were kids,
他一个人打死了一条眼镜蛇
He killed a cobra all by himself.
村里头的人觉得他霸道得很
Everyone in the village thought he's so tough,
就称呼他眼镜蛇，眼镜蛇
We called him Cobra since then,
后来叫着叫着，就变成眼镜儿了
And it gradually became Bra.
霸不霸道？
Tough, huh?
你给她两个说这些咋子？
Why do you tell her that?
这些翻都翻篇了的老事情
Old stories should be left behind.
就莫再提了
Stop dredging them up.
不要跟她两个说话
Don't talk to her.
好
Fine.
你吃不吃饭？
Do you want some food?
欸老子喊你不要张她
I said don't talk to her!
好好好
Fine.
吃的饭都是人家的
We're dining in her place.
谢谢啊
Thank you.
你说
Tell me,
这笔手机...
How much can we get
我们卖好多钱呢？
when we sell off these phones?
目前不好说
Can't tell yet,
但是保守估计...
But a conservative estimate would be
20万是应该有的
At least two hundred thousand.
二十万?
Two hundred thousand?
一人一半的话，一人10万嘛
If I get a half share, it makes a hundred thousand.
8万来装修房子
Eighty thousand to redecorate the house;
两万钱做彩礼
Twenty thousand for bride token.
7万块钱装修房子
Or seventy thousand for redecoration;
2万块钱做彩礼
Twenty thousand for bride token;
1万钱买棒棒糖
Ten thousand for lollipops.
霞爱特别爱吃棒棒糖
Xia loves lollipops.
我要跟你说好多回
I've told you millions of times,
她不可能嫁给你
She won't marry you.
更别说跟你回乡下去过日子
Let alone going back to the village with you.
唉，你那么肯定啊?
Why are you so sure?
以前是没得钱
We didn't have money before,
现在有钱了
But now we do,
情况就不一样了嘛
That makes a difference.
这不光是钱的问题，兄弟
It's not about money, dude.
她为啥子要进城？
Why did she come to the city?
我们为啥子要进城？
Why did we come to the city?
就是在乡下待不下去了撒
Because we couldn't live in the village.
人往高出走
Water streams downwards
水往低处流
While men strive for somewhere higher.
说白了，进城就是要换个活法
A city life is a different way of living,
就是要板命
We'll have to fight for it.
而且我们现在第一枪已经打响了
Our very first shot has been fired,
接下来应该啷个做
Here's what we gonna do next.
等这批货一出手
As soon as we manage to sell the goods,
先拿钱把装备更新
We'll use the money to upgrade our gears,
摩托车、
Motorcycles,
头盔、
Helmets,
子弹、
Bullets,
枪！
Guns.
老子整把AK
I'll get an AK for myself,
给你弄把来福
And a rifle for you.
日你的魂哦
fuck your soul
做大做强~
We'll become bigger and stronger.
再创辉煌
Stand on the peak of success.
六万块钱装修房子应该够了哇?
Is sixty thousand enough for redecorating the house?
办大事，办大事，办大事！
Ambition, ambition!
我晓得
I know.
娶霞妹儿就是我最大的事
Marrying Xia is my biggest ambition.
抢都抢了
Since you're robbers,
为啥子不抢银行，要抢个手机店儿啊
Why didn't you rob the bank, but a phone store instead?
手机店儿好抢
It's easier to rob a phone store.
没有保安
There's no security guard.
就是不敢抢银行嘛
So you don't have the guts to rob banks.
还不承认
Admit it.
是的，就是不敢
No, we don't.
谁说不敢？
Who said it?
老子啥子不敢
Of course we do,
时机还没有成熟哒嘛
But it's not yet the right time.
我们现在刚刚入行
We're newcomers in this business,
起步要稳
We need a solid start,
一步一个脚印儿的来
And achieve higher step by step.
听到没得？
Got it?
一步一个脚印儿的来
Step by step.
我要是你们
If I were you,
第一步抢劫
I'll take robbery as the first step,
第二步，就是应该杀人
And murder the second step.
你为啥子，非要我们杀你喃？
Why do you want us to kill you so badly?
你有好想结婚，我就有好想死
I want to die as much as you want to marry your girl;
你有好想当大哥，我就有好想死
As much as you want to be the big brother.
你们一枪打死我你们就可以出去了
You guys can go out once you shoot me dead.
一步一步，做大做强。
Step by step, bigger and stronger.
而且我跟你们说
I'll tell you what,
你们杀死我是做好事
Killing me is like doing justice.
是助人为乐，传出去不丢人
It's not shameful to let people know you're helping people.
而且我还可以把我的钱都给你们
I can give you all my money as well.
一举两得
It's kill two birds with one stone.
三得~
Three birds!
我说的有没有道理
Does that make sense?
你们个人想一下
Think about it.
你们不打死我
You can't go
你们就走不到哦
If you don't kill me.
你走我就喊
I'll shout if you try to leave,
一喊你们又出不门去了
Then you'll have to stay here for longer.
结果就是
The three of us
下半辈子我们三个就在这个屋头
Will end up in this flat.
相依为命
We'll feed each other,
等死
While waiting for death.
我是无所谓哈，我习惯了
I'm already quite used to it,
卷毛毛儿
But you, curly hair,
你不是想结婚吗?
Don't you want to get married?
你想结婚你只能和我结婚
You'll have to marry me instead.
鸡冠头
Chicken-head,
你不是想当大哥么
Don't you want to be the big brother?
你要当大哥
The curly hair
你只能当卷毛毛儿勒大哥
Will be your only gangman,
反正我是不会服你滴
I'll never obey your orders anyway.
永远
Never!
老子！
What the...
哎呀
Jesus...
咋个又来了哦
Not again!
欸，眼镜儿，眼镜儿
Stop it, Bra.
莫搞了，莫搞了好不好
Stop it, will ya?
对头
That's right.
开枪打死我
Shoot me dead.
各自欢喜
Everyone'll be happy.
唉呀，唉，你看看，你看看
Hey, take a look!
这个墙上写的多好啊
There's good saying on the wall.
人生就像一场戏
'All the world's a stage'
因为有缘才相遇
'Men and women merely players'
别人生气我不气
'But if you're in rage'
气出病来无人替
'No one's happier than your haters'
晓不晓得？
Understand?
莫生气
No rage!
有道理...
It makes sense.
句句都黑有道理
Every sentence makes sense.
但是也不是没得漏洞
But it doesn't mean your logic's perfect.
等于是你永远不会睡着么？
Will you never fall asleep?
她睡着了我们就走了撒
We'll go once she falls asleep.
啊，好大个事嘛
Big deal.
吓哪个嘛
I pissed my pants.
是勒,是勒
Yes, yes.
不就是时间问题么
It's just a matter of time.
莫生气
No rage.
躺起
Nap time.
警察叔叔，我真的没有抢劫
I'm really not the robber, sir!
我也不知道你说的那个枪在哪里...
I've no idea where your gun is!
说真话会不会？
Speak properly, will ya?
会不会说真话？会不会？
Will ya?
会不会说真话？
Will ya speak properly?
会不会？
Will ya?
会！
Yes!
会不会！？
Will ya?
会~
Yes!
会啊，会啊
Yes, yes.
我说的绝对是真话
I'm saying the absolute truth.
手都遭打断了
They broke my arm,
咋可能去抢劫嘛...
How could I be the robber?
以后，再敢欺负真真
From now on, if you mistreat Zhenzhen,
老子，见你一次，打你一次
I'll beat you up every time I see you.
晓不晓得？
Got it?
晓得了，晓得了
Got it!
晓得啥子？
Got what?
以后看到真真
When I see Zhenzhen,
我喊她妈~
I'll call her my mom!
欸，不要打了不要打了
ah, don`t hitting me ,don`t hitting...
打老子一顿
They beat me up,
还把老子勒头盔抢起走了
And took my helmet too.
真真？
Zhenzhen?
这个真真是哪个？
Who's Zhenzhen?
是我妈...
She's my mom.
no,no,no,no,no
别，别，别，别，别
她，她等于在我们那儿当技师...
She's one of our massagists.
在哪儿可以找到这个真真
Where can I find this Zhenzhen?
梦巴黎撒！
Le Rêve Parisien!
我们那里足底，推油，SPA，
We do foot massage, oil massage and SPA,
前列腺保健
Prostate massage.
统统五折哦
Half price for all!
大哥，我带你去嘛
I'll take you there, buddy!
贵宾你好
Hello, sir.
那就坦白从宽
Leniency to those who confess.
你在这儿做啥子？
What are you doing here?
说话！
Answer it!
警察真的会这样问话？
That's how real cops interrogate people?
会不会太粗鲁了哦?
Is that too rude?
那不然咋问嘛？
How then if that's wrong?
万一被警察抓到了
If we are arrested,
我们一定要对好口供
We'll offer a sincere confession.
cosplay
Cosplay
得多加钱哦
Costs extra.
钱不是问题!
Money's not a problem!
姓名？
Name?
王顺财
Wang Shuncai.
年龄?
Age?
Fifty-six.
你们是非法性交易
You've committed illegal prostitution.
哎哟
Ouch...
那这么说还有合法性交易了哦？
There's a 'legal' prostitution then?
两个人光起身子不嫖娼咋子安？
Aren't you having sex when you both are naked?
光起身子就是嫖娼 ？
Nudity doesn't mean sex.
我走错澡堂子了
I got into a wrong bathhouse,
我光起身子被女人看到了
The woman saw me naked,
那到底是我嫖了哪个女的
Who is the prostitute in this case,
还是那个女的嫖了我？
The woman or me?
你好...
Hello, sir.
大叔...
Daddy!
你这个谎话说的实在是太牛了
What an eloquent lie!
我跟你说嘛
I'll tell you what,
就算警察真的把你抓进去了
Even if the cops really get you,
他也，亲自送你出门~
They'll escort you out themselves.
等一下，等一下，等一下
Wait a sec!
大叔，你是不是变态啊
Are you a pervert, daddy?
你来这儿做啥？
What're you doing here?
在哪儿?
Where?
这儿
Here!
拯救地球
Saving the planet.
你说啥？
What?
我跟你说
I'll tell you what,
你们这个地球啊
Your planet
遇到大问题了
Has got a huge problem;
拯救地球唯一的办法
The only way to save it
就是不停和男人睡觉...
Is to keep sleeping with men.
你可不可以，严肃一点点...
You gotta be more serious.
好嘛
Fine.
我们来一盘...严肃的...哈
Let's go for a serious round.
姓名？
Name?
真真
Zhenzhen.
哪个真？
How to spell?
真假勒真
Z-H-E-N.
警察来了!
Cop's here!
警官，警官，误会了
Sir, it's a misunderstanding!
我们正拯救地球
We are saving the planet.
我是常规按摩
I was doing regular massage,
他把我衣服脱了
But he took my clothes off.
你乱讲啥？
What the hell!
警官,我……
Sir, I…
马哥?
Ma?
我错了，我错了
I'm sorry!
咋个是你？
What are you doing here!
我今天我生日，我第一次来
It's my birthday. It's my first time here.
第一次
First time.
闭嘴！出去！
Shut up. Get out.
要的，要得！
Yes, sir!
我...我对不起嘉琪
I beg Jiaqi's pardon.
滚
Get lost!
好
Alright.
我在外面等你
I'll wait for you outside.
你是哪个？
Who are you?
你有两个朋友很危险
Your two friends are in danger,
他们让我来找你
They asked me to find you.
啥子朋友？
Which friends?
他们才帮你打了波仔嘛
They just helped you beating up Bobby.
他们帮你打了波仔
They beat up Bobby,
拿了支枪
They got a gun,
抢劫了手机店
And robbed a phone store.
现在不光是波仔在找他们
Not only Bobby's looking for them now,
警察也在抓他们
But also the cops.
只有我能帮他们
I'm the only one who can help.
咋可能嘛?
How's that possible?
李大头胆这么小
Big Head is a coward
咋可能去抢劫嘛？
How could he be a robber?
李大头变了
Big Head has changed.
你是哪个?
Who are you?
我是他们同伙
I'm part of their gang.
啥子同伙？
What gang?
我现在没得时间跟你解释
I have no time to explain,
他们在哪儿嘛?
Where are they?
喂，领班，领班你过来
Manager, come here,
这儿有个很奇怪...
This guy's weird!
你咋子嘛
What are you doing?
领班！
Manager!
干啥子
Don't do that!
你莫喊！
Don't yell!
领班...唔~
Gosh!
大头真的有枪!
Big Head really has a gun!
那个枪是我的!
The gun's mine!
我不骗你
I'm not lying.
只有我能帮到他
I'm the only come who can help him.
警察查房，查房！
Police!
好嘛
Fine.
耗撒
Let's wait.
耗下去，吃亏是你们
Keep waiting and you'll loose.
我怕个锤子
I'm not afraid at all.
为啥子说...吃亏的是我们？
Why will we loose?
现在的手机，都有定位功能
Nowadays every phone has a location tracker,
你们抢来的那些手机，都关机没得嘛
Have you switched off all the phones you've robbed?
都关了吗？
Did you?
每一个都关了吗？
Is every phone off?
我怕警察已经走到楼脚了
I'm afraid the cops are already at the corner of this building
这个关了
This one's off.
这个没关
This one's not!
二楼了啊
The second floor now.
关机，关机，关机，关机！
Switch that off!
要敲门了哦
They'll knock the door.
轻点儿，轻点儿
Be careful.
哎呀，轻...
You'll break them!
不可能，不可能
That's not possible.
都是模型
They're all models.
你咋子？
What are you doing?
两个憨批
You two idiots!
一步一个脚印儿
'Step by step'!
做大做强，做大做强
'Bigger and stronger'!
男人要做大事
'Men should have ambitions'!
大事~做大事~
'Ambitions'!
眼镜儿
Bra.
大头
Big Head.
头盔侠
Helmetmen!
我不笑了
I'm not laughing any more.
你……
What...
现在啥子想法嘛？
What are you thinking?
老子要看电视满
I want to watch TV.
老子想死
I'm thinking about death.
你在这里做啥子
Don't cram yourselves here,
往里头走
Move along.
走，走，走，走
Move, move.
手抱头
Hands on the head.
蹲起，蹲起
Get down.
哪个晓得，你们领班儿波仔在哪里？
Who knows where Bobby is?
哪个晓得波仔在哪里？
不晓得
Dunno.
马哥
Ma,
我帮你做哈证
I can be your witness.
这个事情
You have to know how to quibble
一定要懂得狡辩
In this situation.
你在这做啥子?
What are you doing here?
你来做啥子？
警官
Sir,
都这么熟了
Since you know each other so well,
通融一下
Please do us a favour.
哪个喊你说话勒！？
I'm not talking to you!
马先勇
Ma Xianyong,
哑巴了吗？
Have you lost your tongue?
队长，算了嘛
Forget it, captain.
走，走，走
Go, go.
消消气，我来
Let me deal with this.
走，走，走，走
Take a rest.
马先勇
Ma Xianyong,
今天啥子日子
What day is it today?
咋个哪里都有你？
Why are you everywhere?
起来，起来，起来
Get up, get up.
手扶起
Hold others' back.
快点儿，快点儿，走了
Hurry up.
嘿,大哥
Hey buddy,
我手机还在房间里头，我去拿一下
My mobile's in the room, I gonna get it.
少说废话
Cut the crap.
手扶起
Hands up.
穿个皮有啥子了不起
He thinks wearing uniform makes him boss?
走！
Move.
你这个情况会不会被拘留哦？
Will you be held in detention,
马哥
Brother Ma?
哪个是你哥
I'm not your brother.
我们现在是患难兄弟
We're now brothers-in-arms,
万一你被拘留了
Once you're held in detention,
我会好好照顾佳琪的
I'll take good care of Jiaqi.
不要跟我提佳琪
Don't mention Jiaqi.
你要再敢去找她
If you dare to visit her again,
老子打死你
I'll beat shit out of you.
你听到没有
You heard that?
你房租咋算呢
But how about your sister's rent?
收我的彩礼金咋算呢？
You've already accepted my bride token.
那是你龟儿借给老子的
I borrowed it from you.
你神经病啊
Are you out of your mind?
是你说你妹结婚需要房子
You said your sister needs a house to get married,
我才给你的
That's why I gave it to you.
你妹不嫁给我
Why the hell should I lend you all that,
我借个毛给你
If your sister's not marrying me?
你妹是个残废
Your sister's a cripple,
我包十万块钱已经对的起你了
A hundred thousand for bride token is already a lot!
上午装死骗钱
You played dead like a swindler this morning,
下午就跑起来找小姐
And came here to hook up in the afternoon.
找个小姐回去给依依当后妈么？
Are you finding a hooker to be Yiyi's stepmother?
不要说我的事情
Leave my case alone,
这个案子我有线索
I have clues about the robbery.
你还想当协警？
Still fancy getting into auxiliary police unit?
你当个锤子！
Forget about it!
废人一个
You're such a waste.
拷起
Cuff him.
下来
Get off.
过来两排，往里面走
Get inside in two rows.
快点快点
Get down.
快点儿
Hurry up.
走快点儿
Speed up.
下来跟到起
Follow neatly.
任叔...
Uncle Ren.
依依你咋来了？
Why are you here, Yiyi?
我有个事想跟你说
I wanna tell you something.
这边有点儿乱，来我们过来说
It's a bit messy, come over here.
啥子事？
What's up?
高翔他们几个...
Gao Xiang and his mates...
啥子事嘛？
What's happening?
就是...
Well...
依依
Yiyi.
大人的事情你不要管
Don't worry about adults' business.
那个…我们，我们
We…
你在这儿咋
What are you doing here?
你不上学，在这儿做啥子安？
Why aren't you at school?
你呢?
And you?
不要管我，回学校
Don't worry about me. Go back to school.
丢人
Shame.
站起来，走，走，走
Get up and move.
这搞错了，这是误会
It's a misunderstanding.
烂人!
You arsehole.
老杂种
Bastard!
那我也是你老子
I'm your dad!
咋跟爸爸说话勒
Don't talk to your dad like this.
他才不是我老子
He's not my dad!
我早就不姓马了
I have nothing to do with this guy,
我改了跟我妈姓了
I changed my surname to my mom's.
你说啥子?你说啥子？安？
What did you say?
马先勇，你对不起我妈!
Ma Xianyong, you've failed my mom!
你对得起你妈？
How about you?
你对得起你妈？啊？
Have you not failed her yourself?
她打老子?
She slapped me?
依依!
Yiyi!
你在做啥子嘛?
What are you doing？
我们把这些东西还回去
We bring these back,
把该拿的东西拿回来
To find our own stuff.
把啥子东西拿回来嘛
Find what stuff?
尊严
Our dignity.
你要干啥子嘛...
What do you want?
老子要杀人
I want to kill someone.
不要去闹了，好不好，啊？
Will you stop looking for troubles?
我求求你了
Please.
把我逗起玩...
Am I kidding you?
批那个狗日勒营业员
That shop assistant,
明明晓得是假手机，他龟儿也不说一声
He knew those were models but didn't say a word.
嫩是看到我们在那拿锤子敲了尼玛半天
Just watched you bust a gut to crack the glass.
哪个逗起拿?
Who was kidding you?
妈模型机，拿尼玛梆硬的，梆硬的玻璃罩起咋子？
Who on earth put models under a hard glass cover?
耍老子是不是？
Was that a prank?
要的
Fine.
老子让他龟儿血债血偿
I'll let them pay with blood.
你要杀人先把我杀了
Kill me first if you want to kill someone.
就当练个手
Make it a rehearsal.
我现在没得心情跟你两个扯
I'm not in the mood to bullshit with you two.
我喊人了啊
I'll shout to get someone.
唉，她要喊人了啊
She'll shout.
随求她喊
Off her shout.
不要闹了，不要走了好不好
Please don't leave.
你去不去？
Are you coming?
你不去，我一个人去
I'll go alone if you don't.
我不去
I'm not going,
你也不要去
And neither are you.
放手!
Let go of me!
你不要去，不要去
Don't go, don't!
两个戴头盔的劫匪
Two robbers with helmets
一个拿刀，一个持枪
One with a knife and one with a gun
冲进了他照片里的这家手机店
Broke into this phone store in the photo
更搞笑的事情在后头
The funniest thing is
据手机店的店员介绍说
According to the seller
这两个人，雄赳赳，气昂昂的
These two dashed into the phone store
就冲进了手机店
With their formidable look
而且还装模做样的
And even fired a shot
朝到天花板开了一枪
At the ceiling
结果呢，抢的是一堆...
But what they robbed were
不值钱的手机模型
A chunk of models which don't worth a penny
这个消息很快就被传到了网上
This news was soon uploaded online
网友呢就评论说，啊
The comments said that
这俩人儿，抢砸手机
The two fake-phone-robbers
这智商肯定是负数吧
Must possess a negative IQ
还有网友，把他们评为了
They were also rated online.
年度最蠢劫匪
As the retarded robbers of the year.
更有热心的网友
Someone also made them
为他们制作了一段鬼畜的视频
An auto-tuned video
让我们一起来欣赏一下
Let's take a look
老子要去把电视台炸了！
I'm gonna blow up the TV station!
老子要去炸电视台
滚开!
Get lost!
老子要把他炸死！
I'm gonna blow him up!
把他全部炸翻！
I'm gonna blow the shit out of them all!
我日你妈卖麻麻批
fuck your mother
嗯，老子要犯法，你...
I break the law,
你来抓老子...
Come and get me!
你关老子，枪毙老子...
Put me in jail, shoot me dead!
老子都认账呀...
I'll take it all!
你为啥子
But why did you
你为啥子要恶搞我...
Why did you auto-tune me?
你侮辱我...
And humiliate me.
你为啥子要耍老子...
Why did you make fun of me?
走
Go.
走嘛
Just go.
不是要走吗？
Don't you want to leave?
走嘛，我不喊了
Go, I won't shout.
你们……
You...
你们两个走嘛
You guys can go now.
你在咋子？
What are you doing?
大头？
Big Head?
你咋子？
What are you doing?
你不要动我！
Don't touch me.
你咋子？
What are you doing?
你咋子？不要！
Don't do that!
你不要过来！
Don't come here!
你不要看我啊！
Don't look at me!
你要咋子！？
What do you want?
你不要动我！
Don't touch me!
你走过来试一下，试一下！
Don't you ever take a step forward！
你敢过来你试一下！
Don't you ever touch me!
你不要看我
Don't look at me!
你不要过来啊
Don't!
求求你了
Please!
你不要过来
Don't!
我不用啊，我不用！
I don't need you.
不要过来！
Don't!
听见没得，不要过来！
Did you hear that?
我求求你...
I beg you!
不!
Don't!
别动我！
Don't touch me!
日你妈！
fuck you mother
fuck you mom
不用你管
I don't need you!
不要过来
Don't!
滚！你滚啊！
Fuck off!
你咋子？
Don't touch me!
不要动我...你不要动
don`t touch me ,don`t touch
你滚！
Fuck off！
我日你妈！
I Fuck your mother！
我日你妈呀！啊~~~
I fuck your mother aaaaa!
刘红
Liu Wenhong,
我晓得
I know,
我亏欠你好多...
I owe you a lot.
但是没有办法
But I have to go back,
我就是这么一个人
That's how I am.
你欠他们那么多钱
You owed them so much money,
你不可能还的起的
How can you pay them back?
今天要是回去了
Once you get back today,
他们要弄死你的啊！
They'll have you screwed!
我要是过了这一关
If I get it over this time,
不管你在哪儿
I'll marry you
我都去娶你
No matter where you are.
你个瓜娃子
You idiot!
咋子？
What now?
别动手！
Stop it!
你又动手
Don't start again!
听到！
Stop!
你为啥子非要回去嘛！
Why do you have to get back?
刘武在给我开追悼会
Liu Wu's holding my funeral,
我是主角，我必须回去！
I gotta be back coz I'm the lead of this show!
回去送死嘛?
Be back for death?
让你儿子没得爹，你个憨批！
Your son will lose his dad, you idiot!
老子自从爱上你
My son had lost his dad already
我儿子已经没得爹了！
Ever since I fell in love with you!
你们帮我一下嘛
Please do me a favour.
我求你们了
I'm begging you.
杀人？
We really
我们确实下不去手
Cannot kill you.
你们就当是做好事
Consider it an act of mercy,
可不可以嘛
Will you do that?
我帮你
I'll help you.
死之前
What do you want to do
你还想做点儿啥子？
Before you die?
光落在你脸上
The sun sheds light on your face
可 爱一如往常
Pretty as you always be
你的 一寸一寸 填满 欲望
Your skin slipped in my body, which satisfied my desire
城市啊 有点脏
The city is sort of complicated
路人 行色匆忙
The passengers walk hastily
孤单 脆弱不安 都是 平常
Being alone, delicate, nervous is my routine, day after day
你 低头不说一句
You didin't say a word, face lowered
你 朝着灰色走去
You sank in deep depression
你 住进混沌深海
You moved to chaos in abyssal sea
你 开始无望等待
You start to wait, aimlessly and hopelessly
你 低头不说一句
You didin't say a word, face lowered
你 朝着灰色走去
You sank in deep depression
你 住进混沌深海
You moved to chaos in abyssal sea
你 开始无望等待
You start to wait, aimlessly and hopelessly
快乐 缺点勇气
Happiness lacks a little courage
浪漫 缺点诗意
Romantic needs some poetry
沉默 一句一句 都是 谜题
Silence in every second is a mystery
都清醒 都独立
We are sober and independent
妄想 都没痕迹
Even dreams didn't leave any trails
唉大哥，我手机在房间里头我去拿一下嘛
Hey buddy, my mobile's in the room
我去拿一下嘛
I gonna get it.
少说废话
Cut the crap.
手扶起
Hands up.
姓名？
Name?
真真。
Zhenzhen.
大名
Real name?
赵红霞。
Zhao Hongxia.
哪里人？
Place of origin?
响水县梁桥村柳季寨
Liujizhai, Liangqiao Village, Xiangshui County.
来侨城好长时间了?
How long have you been in Qiaocheng?
五年
Five years.
做啥子工作勒？
Occupation?
在梦巴黎做按摩师
Massagist at Le Rêve Parisien.
我们这里有几张相片
Here are some photos.
帮我们辨认一下
Please help us identifying them.
你看看这个戴头盔的人
These guys with helmets,
有没得印象
Do you recognise them?
看仔细点
Look closely.
戴起头盔，哪个认得到哦？
How can I recognise someone with a helmet?
我给你说，赵红霞
Listen, Zhao Hongxia,
你如果现在那个事情说出来
It'll count as a meritorious service
算是立功
If you tell us right now;
如果我们查出来
But if we find out
你有啥子包庇的话
That you're covering something up,
这个性质就不一样了哦
It'll be a different story.
你喊我说啥子嘛？
What do you want me the say?
好久说的要抢劫
When did they plan the robbery?
同伙是哪个？
Who's in the gang?
把你晓得的全部说出来
Tell us everything you know!
我咋晓得他要去抢劫哦？
How do I know they were gonna rob somewhere.
我最后跟你说一遍哈
I'll repeat one last time,
想到啥子说啥子
Tell us whatever you have in mind.
大脑壳
Big Head,
你在咋子?
What are you doing?
不要闹
Leave me alone,
老子在偷wifi
I'm stealing Wi-Fi.
老子好想
I really want to
一脚把你龟儿踢下去哦
Kick you off the roof!
他是喜欢我
He does like me.
霞妹儿，你电话啷个打不通呢？
Xia, why can't I reach your phone?
你是不是生我气了哇？
Are you mad at me?
我晓得
I know
你在躲我
You're hiding from me.
我跟我兄弟发了誓
I've sworn to my bro,
一定要忘掉你
That I'll forget you.
就当这么多年
I'll take all these years
一场游戏一场梦
As a mere illusion.
如果我要是再找你，我就是憨批
I'll be a dumbass if I ever look for you again.
他说他配不上我
He said he doesn't deserve me.
以为我嫌他不会搞钱
He thought I disliked him coz he can't make money.
他晓得啥子嘛
What does he know?
就是说憨话
He was just saying daft things.
大头
Big Head,
你那个霞妹儿，漂亮吗?
Is your Xia pretty?
漂亮。
Pretty.
漂亮得很
Very pretty.
他说城市太大了
He said the city's too big,
找不到方向
He can't find his way.
他还说 回老家了
He said he'll get back home
就去盖一个房子
And build a house there.
他说要和我结婚
He said he'd marry me.
那你呢?
And you?
你有女朋友没得?
Have you got a girlfriend?
他有个锤子
Of course he doesn't!
龟儿还是个处男。
He's still a virgin.
我放你妈得狗臭屁
Bullshit!
不是哦?
Aren't you?
老子操女勒时候
I was already a womaniser
你娃还在吃鼻屎
When you were still shitting your pants.
唉~滚滚滚滚滚~
Get lost.
我不像他
I'm not like him,
我心思从来不放到那些高头
I never pay attention to this kinda thing.
男、男人要做大事
If a man wants to achieve something big,
先、先要把女人那一关过了
He gotta forget about women first.
龟儿永远懂不起
He'll never get it.
霞妹儿
Xia,
我想通了
I thought it through,
我就是说破天
I'd better do something
也不如做出来
Than saying too much.
我要和我兄弟去做一件大事
I've decided to do something big with my bro.
做完大事，我就回来娶你
I'll come back and marry you after that.
我不晓得他说得就是去抢劫
But I didn't know he meant to rob.
那你说得那个人，是哪个？
Which one are you talking about?
波仔
Bobby.
陈波波
Chen Bobo.
现在给他打个电话
Give him a call,
把他约出来
Arrange him a date.
波仔是刘武的小弟
Bobby is Liu Wu's sidekick,
出了事
If Bobby robbed the stroe,
他肯定要去找刘武
He'll definitely go to Liu.
今晚我要找吴哥
I'll ask Brother Wu tonight
给他借几个兄弟
To gather some men.
老子今天我要报仇！
I'll take revenge!
我今天晚上，我想打哪个打哪个！
I'll smash whoever I want tonight!
走！
Let's go!
你说为啥子会有桥呢？
Why are there bridges?
因为路
Coz the roads
走到头了
Have reached an end.
桥也是路撒
Aren't bridges also roads?
叫着河高头得路
They're roads on top of rivers.
我听说人要下去了
I heard that one has to cross a bridge
也一样要过一座桥
In the purgatory as well.
叫奈何桥
It's called the Bridge of Sighs.
说是人过了奈何桥
Crossing the Bridge of Sighs,
这一辈子就翻篇儿了
One will turn over the page of his life.
差不多了
It's time,
要下雨了
It's gonna rain.
你怎么那么傻，我想...
Such an idiot,...
我想你了，你在哪里?
I miss you, where are you?
霞妹儿！
Xia!
你能想我
You are missing me,
我真勒太高兴了
I'm so happy.
我...
I...
我天天儿都在想你
I miss you every day.
我...我在...
I'm
我在西山大桥...
I'm at Xishan Bridge.
西山大桥这边...
Near Xishan Bridge.
莫怕
Don't be scared.
过了桥
Cross the bridge,
就翻篇儿了
And it'll be over.
李大头
Big Head.
我说了我不帮忙的嘛
I said I'm not gonna help.
我们在西山桥见，我想和你谈结婚得事情，好嘛？
Shall we meet at Xishan bridge...to talk about the wedding.
好，好，好，好，好
OK OK,
见个面，见个面
Let's meet up.
今天晚上见个面
Let's meet up tonight.
8点钟咋样？
How about eight?
8点钟
Eight o'clock.
你咋子？
What are you doing?
还给我，还给我
Gimme back!
你在咋子？
What are you doing?
没有啥子
Nothing.
你做啥子嘛你！？
Why did you do that?
李大头
Big Head,
你这脑壳里面装得是屎吗?
Is your brain filled with shit?
现在外面警察到处在找我们
The cops are looking for us everywhere,
她早不找你，晚不找你
She never dates you any other times
偏偏这会儿找你？
But why now?
还要跟你回乡下去结婚？
She's marrying you back home too?
你龟儿脑壳昏！
You stupid git!
这个就是爱情!
It is love!
我爱你妈卖麻花儿情！
Fuck your love!
她在那个梦巴黎
Don't you know
做啥子你不晓得嗦？
What does she do in Le Rêve Parisien?
做啥子?
What does she do?
Does what?
梦巴黎还能做啥子嘛？
What can she do in Le Rêve Parisien?
搓背吗?
Rubbing backs?
那你说她做啥子？
You tell me what does she do?
坐台！
A hooker!
做鸡！
A whore!
老子不管她以前是做啥子勒
I don't care what she was,
老子只管她以后是做啥子勒
I only care what she will be.
大头！
Big Head!
老子不叫大头
I'm not Big Head,
老子叫李海根！
My name is Li Haigen.
我害过你没得！？
Have I ever done you any harm!
那么多年兄弟伙 害过你没得？
Since we became brothers for so many years?
还是不是兄弟？
Are we still brothers?
你说啥子?
What did you say?
老子不把你当兄弟
I wouldn't have stolen my grandpa's gun
老子我会偷我大爷勒枪？
If I didn't take you as my brother.
老子不把你当兄弟
I wouldn't have robbed the shop with you
老子会跟你打劫？
If I didn't take you as my brother.
老子不把你当兄弟
I wouldn't have helped you bragging for so long
会帮你吹那么多年勒牛批？
If I didn't take you as my brother.
你要出头
You wanna do something big,
你要霸道
You wanna be tough.
你打死一条眼镜儿蛇
You even killed a cobra.
龟儿你当年就是捡了一条死蛇！
You just found a dead snake!
怕是你个人都快忘记了吧？
You've forgotten it yourself, I reckon?
胡广生
Hu Guangsheng.
你要推她下去？
You gonna push her off?
你要帮她跳楼自杀是不是?
You wanna help her committing suicide?
她从上到下，只有脑壳能动
She can't even move except her head,
啷个跳楼自杀？
How can she commit suicide?
你推她下去
Once you push her off
你就是杀人
You've killed someone;
你推她下去
Once you push her off
你就是杀人犯
You'll be a murderer.
老子没得杀人犯的兄弟！
No murderer's my brother!
你叫胡广生?
Your name is Hu Guangsheng?
我叫马嘉琪
I'm Ma Jiaqi.
马嘉琪
Ma Jiaqi.
天要黑了
It's getting dark.
你把煤气打开
You turn the gas on,
就走嘛
Then just leave.
抱一下
Gimme a hug.
小凤儿
Xiaofeng?
你咋子？
What are you doing here?
我要看你啊
To see you.
看完了，走吧
You've seen me. Go now.
我没有看到你嘛
I haven't seen you!
我有啥子好看勒嘛！
There's nothing to see!
小凤儿
Xiaofeng!
小凤不在走咯
Xiaofeng's gone!
凭啥嘛！？
What's her problem?
嫌你臭，嫌你脏？
Was it because of your smell?
别让我看到
Don't let me see her,
看到把腿打断！
I'll beat her leg off!
买菜去了，小凤
She's gone shopping!
还腿打断
Beat her leg off?
你就只会说，只会吹牛
You're bragging again.
我早就想换她了
I wanted to change her long time ago.
不仅想换她
Not only her,
我还想换房子
I wanna change the flat too.
我换个带电梯滴
To somewhere with a lift.
你要卖肾吗?
You gonna sell your kidney for that?
我要干一件大事儿
I gonna do something big.
干完这件大事儿
After this big thing
我就不是我了
I'm not myself no more.
我让你看一下
I'll let you see.
你哥哥
Your brother
不是光会吹牛
Can do something other than bragging.
你要咋子?
What are you gonna do?
我不讲！
I won't tell you.
咋子！?
You gonna do what?
不要问了！
Stop asking!
不讲！
I won't tell you.
再见
Bye-bye.
等一哈！
Wait a sec!
咋了?
What?
你帮他们办事
As for the thing you're helping them,
办不好就算了
Forget about it if it's too hard.
不要勉强，晓得不？
Don't force yourself, you understand?
晓得，晓得
I understand.
走了啊
See you then.
再等一下
Wait!
又咋了?
What now?
依依都上高中了
Yiyi's in high school now,
你不要打她了
Don't beat her any more.
我打她?
I beat her?
她今天打我了，你晓不晓得?
She beat me today, you know that?
为啥子?
Why?
瓜娃子为哈打老子安?
Why did she beat her dad?
我不讲，你去问她
I'm not telling you. Go ask her yourself.
我走了
I'm leaving.
哥哥
Brother!
又咋了嘛?
What now again?
啊算了，你走嘛
Forget it. Just go.
哎呀！
Gosh!
你讲你讲
Tell me.
你得少吃点儿烟
You gotta smoke less,
早饭也要吃
And eat your breakfast.
不要把自己活得乱七八糟的
Don't live in a mess,
晓得不？
You understand?
你咋了?
What happened?
你在说这些?
Why are you talking like this?
咋了嘛?
What happened to you?
马先勇，你好贱哦
Ma Xianyong, you arsehole.
你脑壳是不是有病啊？
Are you dumb or something?
你就是欠骂
You always ask to be insulted.
你被我骂
You never feel good
你才舒服你是不是
When I don't yell at you.
就是！
Exactly.
你别以为
Don't misunderstand
说两句好话你就要上天！
When I'm nice to you for a second.
你要记到
You gotta remember,
我有今天，都是你害的
How I am today was all because of you.
就是你！
It was all you!
你活该你死婆娘，没人管
You deserve to be a widower,
一辈子打光棍儿
No one cares about your life at all!
这就对了嘛
That's right.
这才是你
You're back to yourself.
你也不要咒老子
But don't curse me either,
老子活得好得很
My life's pretty good.
每一天都有人给老子介绍对象
There's always someone introducing me a date,
老子都看不上
But none of them is my taste.
老子今天还去了一趟梦巴黎
I also went to Le Rêve Parisien today.
梦巴黎你晓得不？
You know Le Rêve Parisien?
里头全都是漂亮姑娘
There're lots of pretty girls.
滚吧！
Get lost!
都是大长腿
They all have pretty legs.
滚！
Get lost!
你不要别再来了！
Don't come here anymore!
老子想来就来，想走就走
I'll come whenever I want.
老子是你哥
I'm your brother!
晓得不?
You got that?
走了！
Goodbye!
我原谅他了
I've forgiven him.
我不怪他
I don't blame him.
煤气打开了
The gas is on.
等你睡着了我就走
I'll go when you're asleep.
好听吗?
Is it a good song?
秋天的蝉在叫
In autumn, cicadas are singing
我在亭子边
I'm next to a pavilion
刚刚下过雨
Where it's just been raining
我难在们我喝不倒酒
But sadly I can't drink my wine
我扎实嘞舍不得
I really don't feel like leaving
斗是们船家喊快点走
But the boatman is urging
我拉起你嘞手
I hold your hands
看你眼泪淌出来
See your tears running
我曰拉坟讲不出话来
fuck the tombstone ,I can't talk
我难在们我讲不出话来
So sad that I can't start talking
我要说走喽
Let's go, I say
之千里的烟雾波浪嘞
Through thousand miles of fog and waves
啊黑巴巴嘞天好大哦
The sky so dark, with mass mist surrounding
我一提要克好多年
For many years I'll be away
漂亮的小姑娘些嘞
Pretty girl
都不在我边边喽嘞
You won't be by my side
斗算之日子些再唱安逸
Despite the comfort of the life
我也找不倒人来讲喽
I can find no one for a chatting
未来城，高明，高老板
Gao Ming, the developer of La Lune Bleue,
借钱在手英雄好汉
Borrowed money with his heroism;
借钱不还夫为软蛋
But got away with his cowardice!
各小组注意
Watch out, squads.
波仔的手机信号
Bobby's phone signal
已经到达西山大桥
Has reached Xishan Bridge.
眼睛跟我睁大点儿
Keep your eyes open.
放松点儿嘛
Relax.
避，避，避！
Cover yourself.
有警察
There might be cops.
我就是搞不懂
You know that?
对不起，对不起
I'm sorry.
又咋子安?
What's up?
我紧张
I'm nervous.
紧张啥子安
Don't be.
转过去
Turn around.
我去想上厕所
I wanna go to the loo.
转过去
Turn around.
看到没得?
You see that?
老天开眼让我在这儿碰到他！
God's letting me see him here.
又想打老子
He wanna beat me up again.
上次就是这狗日得
It was this motherfucker last time!
弄他！
Get him.
好像是波仔
That one looks like Bobby.
队长队长
Captain.
发现波仔，正在往牌楼那里走
We spotted Bobby moving towards the arch.
一组，跟起
Squad one, follow up.
二组，跟起
Squad two, follow up.
三组，包抄
Squad three, outflank him.
感谢大家捧场
Thank you all for coming.
我今天在这里沉重悼念
I'm here today to mourn with deep grief,
我勒烂兄弟，龟儿
For my shitty friend and brother,
高明
Gao Ming.
大家为了工作赚钱
We all worked hard to earn our money,
我们一起把他找回来
Let's work together to find him.
大家说，好不好?
Shall we do that?
好！
Yeah!
音乐!
Music!
慢一点儿，慢一点儿，保持距离
Slow down, keep a distance.
准备动手！
Get ready.
高明！还钱！
Gao Ming! Gimmie back my money!
刘武！
Liu Wu!
让开！
Go away.
你在咋子?
What are you doing?
老子弄死你！
I'll blow your head off!
一组，一组，下去看一眼
Squad one, get down and take a look!
啥子情况！
What's happening?
二组，把他盯死！
Squad two, keep your eyes on Bobby,
三组
Squad three, stay where you are,
准备支援
Get ready for back up.
是你狗日的偷了老子的枪？
It's you who took my gun.
给老子打！
Get him!
你是哪个？
Who are you!
放开我!
Let go of me!
高翔！
Gao Xiang!
让开！
Let him go!
滚开!
Get lost!
不要打了
Leave him alone!
刘武！我日你妈！
Liu Wu! fuck your mother !
打！
Get him!
不要打我爸！
Don't touch my dad!
儿子!
Son!
走！
Go away.
快点儿
Hurry up.
走！
Go!
快点儿！走！
Hurry up!
快走！
我们到底是管上头还是管下头啊？
Are we watching upstairs or downstairs?
先抓波仔！
Get Bobby first!
Get Bobby!
高翔！
Gao Xiang!
我们来了！
We're here!
冲啊！！！
Forward, forward!
不要动!
Don't move!
逮到！
Freeze!
不要动！
Don't move!
波仔！枪在哪里？
Bobby! Where's the gun!
枪在哪里？
Where's the gun!
说！
Speak!
小崽崽些
Little bastards.
哪个动老子打哪个！
I'll beat shit out of whoever moves.
三组四组，去几个控制现场
Squad three and four, go control the scene,
请外围的兄弟进来帮忙！
Get the outer circle in and help!
我们要保护学生
We gotta protect the students,
保护好学生！
Protect the students!
你在这儿不要动，听到没得？
Stay here and don't move, hear that?
哪个受伤了？
Who's injured?
哪个受伤？
没事哇？
Are you OK?
你咋个样子?
How do you feel?
你叫啥子名字?
What's your name?
你叫...
What's…
我叫马先勇
My name is Ma Xianyong.
老马?
Ma?
老马
Ma.
这个枪
This gun,
我追到了
I've chased it back.
交给你
I'll leave it to you.
医生呢?
Where's the doctor?
快点喊医生嘛！
Get a doctor here!
你说，你说
Speak, speak.
我现在可以当协警了嘛
Can I join the auxiliary unit now?
可以
Yes.
等一哈
Wait a sec.
任晓聪
Ren Xiaochong,
我再送你一个礼物
Another gift for you.
走吧
Let's go.
老子去医院，做个体检
I'm going for a health check in the hospital.
你这样敷没得用
It doesn't work like this.
要把蛋壳剥了才得行
You gotta peel the egg first.
怪不得
No wonder.
老子揉了一天
I've rubbed it for a whole day
越揉越痛
But it got worse.
快点儿
Hurry up.
站到
Stop.
你，你做啥子？
What are you doing?
你给老子闭嘴
Shut up.
眼镜儿
Bra.
你有啥子事，你冲我来好不好
Let's talk it through if you've got any issue.
老子喊你你闭嘴
I told you to shut up,
老子一枪打死她哈
I'll shoot her dead.
站起来
Get up.
老子现在宣布
I now declare
你俩个从现在开始
That you two from now on
就是两口子了
Are husband and wife.
不管他以后啷个倒憨水
No matter how he acts like an idiot
冒憨气
Or like a fool,
他都是你老公
He always will be your husband.
听到没得？
Heard that?
你要是敢骗他，老子...
If you ever cheat on him, I'll…
老子放不过你
I'll never let you get away.
你黑老子……
You scared me...
唉，不要碰我
Don't touch me.
站到！
Stop.
唉！你腿受伤了还跑那么快
You ran so fast with your wounded leg.
哎呀，疼死我了
Yeah, it hurts so bad.
慢点儿
Slow down.
疼死了
It hurts so bad.
啊痛死我了
It hurts…
你去哪儿了?
Where did you go?
喊你不要乱跑你跑啥子嘛
I told you to stay there.
他们受伤了
They're injured
我去帮忙的嘛
I was helping out.
是的是的,
Yes yes,
帮忙勒
Helping out.
受伤的去救护车
Injured ones go to the ambulance,
你，跟我走
You come with me.
家属
Family members,
下车了，下车了，家属
Family member gets off.
去吧
Go.
家属先下车
Family member gets off.
来，后面的，来跟起
Follow up.
慢点儿
Slow down.
后面还有人上车没得喃？
Is there anyone else coming?
李大头
Big Head.
你是哪个?
Who are you?
这就对了
That's right.
走
GO,
啥子安？
What?
走，走，走
Go, go.
不许动！
Don't move.
我是警察
I'm a cop.
把枪放下
Put the gun down.
你先把枪放下
You put it down first.
让他把枪放下
Tell him to put the gun down.
眼镜
Bra,
把枪放下
Put your gun down.
你喊他先把枪放起
Tell him to put it down first.
你先把枪放弃
You put it down first.
叫他把枪放下!
Tell him to put it down!
眼镜，眼镜，你先把枪放起，放起
Bra, put it down please!
他放我就放
I'll put it down when he does.
大哥
Buddy,
我保证你要放枪的话
I promise he'll put the gun down
他肯定会把枪放起
As soon as you do.
他放我就放，他放我就放，他放我就放！
You first.
好好好好好
OK, OK!
一起放
Together.
我数到三
I'll count to three.
一
One.
二
Two.
三
Three.
没子弹了
No more bullets.
枪，没用了
The gun's useless.
崽种...
I'm owned.
哭喊着
Crying out
你睁眼
You opened your eyes
大声笑
Laughing loud
走向前
You marched forward
困惑着
But with confusion
你搁浅
You then stranded
沉默着
In the silence
都幻灭
Everything is disillusioned
在沉浮之间寻找爱的光线
Seeking love's sliver line between ups and downs
阴霾边沿触碰蓝天
The edge of gray haze touched the blue sky
像烟火炙热
Bursting like fireworks
瞬间
Burning
破碎的梦还在不在
Are those broken dreams still here
还给明天一场未来
To bring tomorrow with a future
生命如何充满无奈
Since life is filled with resignation
We should make it bloom in profusion
就当如何怒放精彩
这一个
This
愤怒的疯狂的无名之辈
Angry and crazy cool little fish
执着的刚强的不知后退
Persists and doesn't know how to retreat
坚持着对抗着心中错对
Fights against the wrong in his heart
粉身也不下跪
He refused to kneel, rather be smashed to pieces
卑微的骄傲的我的同类
This humble but proud fish is of my own kind
眼神里不灭的生的光辉
The halo of life sparks in his eyes
誓不做我们世界的鸡肋
He swears not to be encumbrance of our world
碎骨有何可畏
Then what's the fear of break apart
你抬头
You look up
向自由
To the freedom
放开手
You let go
去拥有
To embrace it
在沉浮之间寻找爱的光线
Seeking love's sliver line between ups and downs
阴霾边沿触碰蓝天
The edge of gray haze touched the blue sky
像烟火炙热
Bursting like fireworks
瞬间
Burning
穿过这片幽暗的海
Passing through this shadowy sea
还给明天一场痛快
To bring tomorrow with gratification
黑暗中寂静的等待
Wait silently in the dark
渺小的梦终会盛开
Even the smallest dream shall blossom
这一个
This
愤怒的疯狂的无名之辈
Angry and crazy cool little fish
执着的刚强的不知后退
Persists and doesn't know how to retreat
坚持着对抗着心中错对
Fights against the wrong in his heart
粉身也不下跪
He refused to kneel, rather be smashed to pieces
卑微的骄傲的我的同类
This humble but proud fish is of my own kind
眼神里不灭的生的光辉
The halo of life sparks in his eyes
誓不做我们世界的鸡肋
He swears not to be encumbrance of our world
碎骨有何可畏
Then what's the fear of break apart